[music]
>> Oh, hey.
Hello. Hi. Welcome. I'm Fiddling Johnny.
It's my fiddle channel and magic product
review. Now, today I'm going to do a
review of a magic product called
Holistic.
It is produced by Penguin Magic and put
out by Michael John. Anyway, I have a
lot to say about this release.
I'll show you a demo of it as well. So,
stick around.
And we'll get right into it.
All right, here's my quick intro for the
demo. Uh I used three different style or
size um
uh
things to to penetrate the bill.
You'll see they're relatively large, I
think, compared to what the trailer is.
I do think something smaller like the
uh toothpick uh works best. Um although
he uses a skewer in his, the skewer I
use is a little bit big.
Uh and um I think it works a little bit
better when you use it on the green
circle rather than on the black circle
on the bills that I used. So, anyway,
take a look. You'll see what it's like.
Following that, we'll get right into the
review.
All right, let's do a quick
demo of Holistic. Well, it's a
uh
Was that Andrew Jackson on there?
I think so. Let's go ahead and
we will focus on here. I've got a giant
skewer. Skewer is what is recommended.
I pick the this right here in the
middle.
Hopefully, you can see this. I think
it's lit well up.
And we're going to puncture it
right through.
You can see that actually
has gone through.
It's no small hole.
We'll remove the skewer.
You can actually see how how dimple it
is there.
And
you can actually see through it, right?
All right, but let's just do this.
Let's rub a little
rub. We can begin
to heal
the actual bill.
And
there you go.
It is
totally restored.
Well, almost totally restored here.
And there you go.
It is restored.
You can see that's a pretty big stick.
I'll call this one
a fail for me.
>> [clears throat]
>> I don't know if you can see it or not,
but to me there's still just a little
bit of a hole that is showing.
It feels good to the
touch test,
but it feels like to me the skewer I
used was probably a little bit big. And
may or may not work. You can decide for
yourself
based upon how it looks to you.
All right.
Let's do another one.
Let's do it with something a little bit
different.
Let's do it with a different bill.
All right.
It's a different bill.
And this time I'm going to use a
chopstick. Same sort of thing
right here.
I actually find the
piercing part
the most difficult.
That's good. You can actually see the
hole
through
through the bill.
But, let's go ahead.
That's a pretty giant hole right there.
Let's go ahead
and restore that.
And it's simple as that.
You can see
we've restored
that hole.
I'd say that one was a little bit
better.
And yeah, I think that one's fine.
I would use that. I'd feel comfortable
handing that to my
uh
participant. They can touch and feel
and see that the hole is fine. I would
go next with what I think is the
easiest,
and that is a toothpick. Um
So, hold on. Let's grab the toothpick.
All right, there we go. We have our
Jackson
and we have our toothpick.
Let me do a little bit different. Let's
do it down this side of the bill. It
doesn't really matter. You can do it on
any part of the bill.
And let's
puncture it.
You can actually hear it puncture.
You can see it go through.
We can actually push this all the way
through if we wanted to.
It is actually puncturing
that bill. You can see the light behind
it.
And
let's just do a very quick
restore on that.
All right, and there we go. You can show
both sides.
And
I think that one looks pretty good.
Well, I take that back. I think it looks
average.
But, I think it would it would pass.
All right, there are your demos.
Three different sizes.
Hope that helps a little bit.
All right, welcome everyone
back to the channel. So glad you're
here. I think if I've done this
correctly, you should have just seen a
demo of it so that you have a sense of
what it looks like. I'm I'll apologize
in advance for my voice. I've had a
cold.
I'm still getting over it. I'm thinking
about putting some bloopers at the end
of this because I tried to record this
maybe about a week ago when I didn't
have any voice and quickly realized I
couldn't post anything. All right, let's
talk about holistic.
Holistic is a download
from Penguin Magic.
And it's released by Michael John. And
let me just say, Michael John might be
the most handsome man in magic. Now, I
don't normally critique looks for what
they look like, but
damn, he and I both have this challenge
in magic like we're great looking
handsome people. And sometimes people
just can't see the magic to the beauty
that we
put out there. But, anyway, one of the
things that struck out stuck out to me
is that
sometimes uh
magicians might seem a little nerdy. He
does not put off any nerdy vibe. But,
that's not what we're here for. What
we're here for is this a good
release or not a good release? Is it a
good effect or not a good
good effect?
Uh already you know what the effect is.
It's essentially a bill penetration
where you take an object, penetrate it
through a bill. It is taught in the
tutorial and encouraged to use a skewer.
The type of skewer you might use when
you're barbecuing or maybe when you go
to a restaurant and they're skewering
the chicken on it. That's what he uses.
Um when I've mostly been performing it
and I have,
I just use little toothpicks. Um easier
for me to carry
and I know that I get um
I feel safer and more comfortable with
those. So, uh but basically it's a
penetration effect with a restoration of
the bill. And these are the three bills
that you would have seen in the
demonstration um
with them all
um
restored. All right, that's what the
effect is. What do you get? All right,
you're going to get a streaming video.
The streaming video is 26 minutes and 48
seconds in length. Seems pretty adequate
to me uh for what this is. Uh the skewer
and paper money are not included. I kept
looking for that in the download, but
clearly there's no paper money that that
is included in the download. I know,
sorry to disappoint you, but
maybe that should be obvious. Uh it's
basically it's just a download. We
should talk about how else the tutorial
is because that's maybe
the second most important thing in this
uh
uh relative to method and what it looks
like. So,
uh
it's taught by Michael John himself. Uh
he does a nice multi-cam. It's pretty
straightforward. You're going to learn
the basic routine and then there are
additional three other routines and they
are a moving hole uh routine that is
inspired by Daniel Garcia's fraud
routine. In my opinion, that is the best
one on this release. Um I haven't been
actually out performing that one, but I
do like it uh where you do a
penetration,
uh
make the hole, uh and then have the hole
move essentially. So, it healed and then
moved.
Uh that is uh essentially what that one
is. The second one is a um
let's see.
A whole trans transposition.
>> [snorts]
>> And um
Sorry, that's the three. It's the
original routine, which is space
penetration and restored, a whole
uh
a moving hole routine, and then the
whole transposition
uh routine. Um that's it. That's the
sort of uh what you're getting
routine-wise. I think at the end of the
day, the tutorial's a fine tutorial.
Looks great, you get the method.
You don't need lots of nuance there. Um
some of the subtleties that folks might
be interested in, US money.
Um best if it's not super old
uh and not super brand new, but
somewhere in the middle is most ideal.
Let's talk about how is the gimmick?
There is no gimmick. Nada. Um which I
think is one of the things about this
release, if you're interested, that if
you want to be completely organic with a
borrowed bill or your own bill, uh
without having to attach anything extra,
having to do uh your prep work in
advance, that sort of stuff. Nope, all
you need to do is have a uh paper bill
as well as something to puncture it
with, ideally a skewer.
Um
This cannot be done with uh polymer
bills.
Um I Although it's not set explicitly,
it is would be my understanding, and I
should have gone back to double-check on
the um
uh on the ad copy, but I believe it can
only be done with US paper currency or
paper currency similar to the US
currency. Can't be done with this
polymer beer bills and plastic bills. Um
I don't have those. I haven't tried it,
but based upon the tutorial, I can't
imagine that those would work there.
I would uh
add about presentation.
Um if you purchase this uh you would
learn this in the tutorial, so I'm
giving a slight bit away here. Is that
and I said it earlier is that he really
does prefer the skewer
as opposed to a toothpick even though
like I think the skewer in his was
slightly thicker than my toothpick and
round skewer mine's a squared-off skewer
because the size of the skewer tends to
have a psychologically greater impact
than using maybe a toothpick that might
be just as thick, but the size and
length of the skewer seems to have a
greater psychological effect.
I don't carry skewers with me locally,
so I think uh
normally I do think people might have
toothpicks or if they're
um out with their friends at a bar or
restaurant, toothpicks will probably be
a little bit easier to access.
So, what's the skill level? This is 100%
beginner. There's no slides involved.
There's no moves involved.
Uh there's just a method. So, it all
comes down to your performance. So, you
could be uh
uh performing this
seconds after you watch the tutorial. Uh
so, let's talk about like what are the
pros and cons and things I wish I'd
known uh before purchasing or if I were
on that side of it. Um I'm struggling a
little bit here on this one.
Cuz here uh so, just stick with me.
Let's you and I have a conversation.
When I saw the method, I went
Is that it?
Are you kidding me? Really? It's It's
that simple?
And I know my magician brain went into
full gear. It's like,
it's that simple. It cannot be
effective.
And um
but then I went and performed it.
Cuz I honestly thought the method seemed
so weak to me and like has not somebody
thought of this before and I'm not aware
of somebody using this method in the
past.
But it's so simple. It's hard for me to
believe that people haven't tried this
before and failed and that like Michael
John's succeeding at it. And I sort of
thought like, this
there's no way this will fly.
But then I performed it for somebody and
yeah,
they
were really surprised.
And I'm like, look at the bill cuz I
really sort of, you know, was kind of
hoping I might be discovered.
Um no. Playing around with the bill,
touching the bill? No.
Uh
Um totally fine. To them, they saw a
full restoration.
Um and then I went and I performed it a
couple more times
with same results.
Um each time
um fooling my spectator.
So, I have to admit that I was wrong. Oh
my god, I can't believe I just said
that. I might have to edit that out. Um
>> [clears throat]
>> It's hurting my throat. Let me grab a
drink.
That's a good drink.
Um
yeah. So, I This is one of those times
where my
magician thinking, I think, really got
in the way and that
um it fooled my spectators.
So,
there's that. I don't know if I uh love
it,
um but I know I'm going to use it. So,
um
yeah, so there's that. Um
Yeah.
All right, let's say you're thinking
about purchasing this.
Um
some things for you uh
to consider.
Um
is that
it's not technically fully restored.
There's still a little bit of hole
there. And I would think people would
see it and they don't. Um
after doing this and practicing on
multiple bills as well,
um
in the tutorial and I think in the
teaser they use a um
torch on your cell phone. As if that's
to add this other layer of like look. Um
I'm not sure
that using a torch is necessary from
your phone.
It's used in a way to show like, "Look,
you can actually see through the bill."
I found that people can see through the
bill no problem. I can just wave my
hand, move it around enough, and they
can confirm there's a hole without using
the torch. Now, when I use the torch, I
have found the torch
after the puncture, before the
restoration, great to shine it on top of
it and see it, shine it from underneath
to see the hole, and it's super clear.
When I am done, my preference
is to just shine from above and not
below. I found when I shine from below,
I can see a little bit of a small hole
that is still there.
So, my recommendation if you purchase
this, I have found using the torch is
not my go-to, not what I would use
because I think it could
expose the method. So, and I think and I
I can't find quite the rationale for
using the phone
that I can
get in a simpler way by people just
looking at the bill, handing them the
beer bill. They see that it's punctured,
you know, and that we're not dealing
with a gimmick um object here at all.
So,
that's some of my thinking on it. Um and
I if you purchase it or you're thinking
about purchasing it, those is what I
have learned so far and hopefully that
would be helpful for you as well.
I think one of the really good things
about this one with the method that's
used
is you can give if it's their borrowed
bill, just give them their bill back and
they can keep it, no problem. They can
touch it as much as they want. They can
feel around
and this is a real upside for it from a
feel point of view, there's no hole
there. And if they quickly look at it,
they don't see any hole, they touch it,
there's no hole and I think that's a
really, really great upside
to this. It's like this extra
uh convincer that the hole has been
restored.
Um
All right, let's sort of wrap up on sort
of this portion. I think
on the upside, man, is it a great EDC.
Meaning EDC is that anytime you're with
somebody who has paper money,
paper money, US currency,
um and you can get access to something
that's small to puncture it, um
it's really great.
Um and I think
it's just fun. It's sort of thing for me
that I think I would perform if I'm out
having drinks with friends
Um and they say, "Hey, can you do
something for me real quick or show me a
magic trick?"
You know, my class guys I didn't bring
anything with me. Oh, let's just do
something organic. And it's perfect for
that scenario. It's great for close-up
which is that would be a close-up
scenario. It's not a parlor, it's not a
stage. This is close-up effect. And so
it's nice that it can be it's truly an
organic type of a
performance. Can be performed 360
degrees, doesn't matter.
There's no issues with there. You start
clean and you end clean cuz there's no
gimmicks involved with this.
I will add as it comes to penetrations,
my personal preference is
called Phoenix released by Hanson Chen
and
uh
High Guard. I've done a review of that,
you can go watch that.
I like that one because it really and
it's close to me in some respects in
that
um [snorts]
I like that one because it feels at the
end like oh, that hole is really really
restored.
I could put the torch underneath it and
probably and be fine with it. The
downside of that one is it's gimmicked.
And maybe somebody will see the gimmick.
I've never had anyone see the gimmick,
but that's quite possible. And
it can be just very slightly knacky
when you're first learning it and
performing it live. Whereas this one is
almost identical in the same respect.
But
there's no gimmicks involved. So, you're
ready to go anytime you have paper money
in front of you. So, that's the the
upside.
It is a download. I'm a firm believer in
downloads. I know that other magic
reviewers say
with the downloads and that they're
dead. I still love downloads. I think
they're great. This download is $19.95.
Think it's available exclusively over at
Penguin Magic.
Um,
I kind of think $20 it's priced slightly
high, personally. I've I've been
struggling like what's the right price
point for this and maybe about $10 would
be my ideal price point.
Maybe 15. 20 feels just a hair high for
me.
But if it's something you're going to be
performing
all the time, it's well worth it.
You've got a method that's true and
blue. Uh, so you sort of have to decide
if that price point is right for you. If
you're going to perform it all the time,
I think it's fine. I do think for
based upon
I struggle again with the method. Uh, is
this method worth $20? Cuz that's what
you essentially what you're purchasing.
So the well, you have to decide if
that's the right amount or not. All
right.
I think that's it. If you purchase this,
boy, I would love to hear your comments
down below. Uh, would genuinely uh,
appreciate it. I haven't watched anybody
else's review of this.
So I don't know what others are saying
out there. Um, I know I've performed it
with surprise. It has fooled my
audiences. I will continue to actually
perform it from time to time, probably
in casual settings. Um, but um, yeah, it
worked. So
that's essentially it. Uh, I do want to
thank Penguin Magic
uh, and Michael John for allowing me to
have it so that I can review it for you.
I hope you can sense my honest take on
this for something that uh, was given to
me uh, to review. But leave your
comments down below, hit that like
button, and subscribe button. I'd really
appreciate it. Thanks everyone for being
here. I'm Fiddlin' Johnny.
Remember to keep fiddling around with
your magic. I'll see y'all next time.
Bye-bye.
>> [music]
>> Hey.